Thomas Henry Seymour Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
- I. Correspondence
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, D., [18-]; (4 items) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, E., [18-]; (9 items) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, F., [18-]; (3 items) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, G., [18-]; (12 items) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, H., [18-]; (7 items) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour from Igelstrom, undated., [18-]; (9 items) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour from Colin Macrae Ingersoll, undated., [18-]; (32 items) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, J., [18-]; (4 items) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, L., [18-]; (6 items) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour (two in French), undated, M., [18-]; (11 item) (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, N., [18-]; (5 items) (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Letter to Thomas H. Seymour; letter to the "Minister of Ordinance of the Government of his Majesty the Emperor of all the Russias," undated, O., [18-]; (2 items) (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour with enclosed news clipping, undated, P., [18-]; (5 items) (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Letters primarily to Thomas H. Seymour (one in French), undated, R., [18-]; (10 items) (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, S., [18-]; (8 items) (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour from Seymour family members, undated., [18-]; (3 items) (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour from his sister, Mary Seymour, undated., [18-]; (13 items) (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Letters from Thomas H. Seymour., [18-]; (15 items) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Letters to and from Thomas H. Seymour, undated, T., [18-]; (2 items) (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour from his cousins Mary Vandervoort and Emily Vandervoort, and one anonymous valentine poem, undated., [18-]; (26 items) (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Letters to Thomas H. Seymour, undated, W., [18-]; (6 items) (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Letters and letter fragments to Thomas H. Seymour (five in French), no signatures or illegible, undated., [18-]; (25 items) (Box 9, Folder 25)
- II. Financial papers
  - Financial papers, including Account Book (1842-1843)., 1835 - 1845; (60 items) (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Financial papers., 1846 - 1855; (39 items) (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Financial papers., 1856 - 1857; (26 items) (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Financial papers., 1858 - 1859; (36 items) (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Financial papers., 1860 - 1861; (28 items) (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Financial papers., 1862 - 1868; (46 items) (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Financial papers., [18-]; (50 items) (Box 10, Folder 1)
- III. Legal papers
  - Legal papers, 1837 - 1859; (24 items) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Legal papers concerning Josiah Clark and James M. Robertson., 1861 - 1862; (6 items) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Legal papers for the estates of Captain Thomas Seymour and Harrison Otis; Timothy Dwightrepresentation of railroad track improvement., [18-]; (15 items) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- IV. Military papers
  - Quartermaster General papers
    - Contracts between Thomas Cooley, John Spencer, and William Goodwinand the Quartermaster General., 1816 - 1837; (7 items) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Quartermaster General papers, 1837; (30 items) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Quartermaster General papers, 1838 - 1843; (21 item) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Military Service Papers
    - Military service papers, 1840 - 1846; (12 items) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Military papers., 1847 - 1848; (39 items) (Box 10, Folder 9)
- V. Printed material
  - Printed material, newspaper clippings., [18-]; (9 items) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Ceremonials, shipping schedules, map of St. Petersburg, and opera advertisement from Thomas H. Seymour's years as Russian ambassador. Some items are written in French and some are in Russian., 1856 - 1858; (8 items) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Circulars, minutes, and advertisements, undated., [18-]; (9 items) (Box 10, Folder 12)
- [18-], VI. Speeches and essays; 14 folders; 407 items
  - Bill H. R. 438, To regulate the pay of the of the army of the United States, and for other purposes with notes by Thomas H. Seymour., December, 1844; (4 items) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Speeches by Thomas H. Seymour, organized and dated., 1848 - 1865; (4 items) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (30 items) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (30 items) (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (62 items) (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (22 items) (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (46 items) (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (31 item) (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (38 items) (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (36 items) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (36 items) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (20 items) (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (30 items) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Speeches and essays, undated., [18-]; (18 items) (Box 11, Folder 7)
- 1844 - 1868, VII. Diaries; 12 folders; 87 items
  - Jottings., [between 1846 - 1868]; (13 items) (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Jottings (five items in French), undated., [18-]; (20 items) (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Jottings (two in French), undated., [18-]; (19 items) (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Description of a Journey made by the American Ambassador Seymour, through Russian in 1858., (1 item) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Autographs of members of Congress, of John Tyler, Respectfully presented to the Historical Society of Connecticut by their obedient servant, Thomas H. Seymour., 1844; (1 item) (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Autographs of members of Congress, of John Tyler, Respectfully presented to the Historical Society of Connecticut by their obedient servant, Thomas H. Seymour., 1844; (1 item) (Box 11, Folder 13)
    Archivists note: researcher copy
  - Thomas H. Seymour's French Exercise Book., [18-]; (1 item) (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Thomas H. Seymour's Diary of Travels, 1858; (1 item) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Loose pages found in Thomas H. Seymour's Diary of Travels. Includes sketches by Seymour and a speech given to the Sigourney Association., [1858?]; (21 item) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Blank diary with interleaved invitations, newspaper clippings, and addresses., 1865; (7 items) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - United, historic, political "logic of facts." Thomas H. Seymour's commonplace book., 1866; (1 item) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Campaign notes. Bought of a Republican for the campaign of 1868., 1867; (1 item) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Commonplace book, undated., [18-]; (1 item) (Box 12, Folder 6)
- VIII. Ephemera
  - Ephemera. Business and calling cards, invitations, poetry, postcards, botanical specimens, newspaper clippings, and theater and concert programs., [18-]; (43 items) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Ephemera. Business and calling cards, invitations, tickets, dance cards, lock of hair, sample of grain from Charter Oak Lodge dedication, 1867. Items are in random order., (386 items) (Box 13)
- IX. Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings., [18-]; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings (copy)., [18-]; (1 item); Preservation note: researchers should use copy to preserve the original. (Box 14, Folder 2)
- X. Personal items
  - Wallet., [18-]; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Notebook (blank)., [18-]; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Notebook (blank)., [18-]; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Notebook with enclosures (names on three scraps of paper)., [18-]; (1 item) (Box 14, Folder 6)
- XI. Henry Seymour papers
  - Henry Seymour papers, letters and receipts., 1827 - 1831; (6 items) (Box 12, Folder 8)
- XXII. Thomas Seymour papers
  - Thomas Seymour papers. Correspondence, receipts, and promissory notes., 1781 - 1816; (13 items) (Box 12, Folder 9)